A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Associates, Harry Rand FA1224
Rockefeller Archive Center
Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Associates, Harry Rand
1965-1976
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rand, Harry
Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman (1910-2004)
Smith, Fred
FA1224
12.91 Cubic Feet 34 letter-sized document boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted in accordance with the 2009 donation of the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact an RAC archivist for further instruction.
Scope and Contents
The years represented in these files saw an increasing emphasis on environmental concerns in the United States – water pollution, air pollution, the disposal of solid waste, recycling, clean energy, and the need to consciously plan for beauty in the environment – areas in which Laurance Rockefeller was intensely interested. Two of the series in this collection – Citizens Advisory Committee on Environmental Quality (CACEQ) and Utilities – deal extensively with these concerns. Additionally, the Fred Smith series contains numerous publications, reports, and speeches on environmental issues either written or delivered by Fred Smith.
There is one series in this collection which does not deal with environmental issues, but rather with the Rockefeller family itself. Between 1969 and 1971, several conferences were held dealing with the public image of the Rockefeller family, conferences which Harry Rand, as Fred Smith's assistant, attended. The proceedings of these conferences, which were recorded verbatim, offer a glimpse into the relationships between the offices of the brothers as well as into how each office viewed and/or represented its principal.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Laurance S. Rockefeller papers were donated to RAC in 2009 by the LSR estate.
Biographical / Historical
Harry Rand was born on June 2, 1913. He served as an executive in the offices of Rockefeller Family and Associates, as an associate of Laurance S. Rockefeller and working specifically as an assistant to Fred Smith. As a result, these files contain far more information about those with whom Harry Rand worked than they do about Harry Rand himself.
Harry Rand died on October 24, 1998. He is buried in Arlington National Cemetery.
Arrangement
The material in this collection is divided into nine series: Correspondence, General Files, Businessmen and Beautification, Citizens Advisory Committee on Environmental Quality (CACEQ), Fred Smith, Grand Teton National Park, Utilities, Rockefeller Family: Public Relations, and Research Material. Two of the series, the Citizens Advisory Committee on Environmental Quality and Fred Smith, are further divided into subseries. This arrangement reflects the original order in which the material was received.
- Correspondence, 1959-1979; 3.04 Cubic Feet 8 letter document boxes
  - Correspondence: A, 1968-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
    Scope and Contents
    Including: Advertising Council, Alliance to Save Energy, American Institute of Architects, American Public Power Association, American Society of Planning Officers, Atlantic Richfield Company
  - Correspondence: B, 1959-1976 (Box 1, Folder 7-10)
    Including: Board Meetings Expense Study, William A. M. Burden, Burson-Marstellar, General
  - Correspondence: C, 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 11-16)
    Including: Center for International Environment Information, Commco PR Inc., Commission on Critical Issues, The Conference Board, Corporation for Public Broadcasting, Council on Foundations
  - Correspondence: E, 1968-1978 (Box 1, Folder 17-19, Box 2, Folder 20-23)
    Including: Edison Electric Institute, Electric Utility Industry, Electric Utility Industry and the Environment, Electric Utility Task Force and the Environment, Engineering Foundation Research Conferences, Environmental Data Bank
  - Correspondence: H, 1970-1976 (Box 2, Folder 24-27, Box 3, Folder 28-33)
    Including: Harlem River State Park Dedication, Hawaii Project, Hawaii-International Center for Science and Technology, Hawaii-Suggestions for an Approach to Financing the Water Transmission Line in South Kohala, Hawaii-The Influence of Transportation on the Quality of Growth in Hawaii, Hawaii-A Problem for the Hawaiian Conscience, Housing Letter, Hudson Highlands State Park-LSR, Hudson River Projects
  - Correspondence: I, 1968-1978 (Box 3, Folder 34-36)
    Including: IBEC Luncheon, Industry/Environment Liaison Project, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers
  - Correspondence: J, 1966-1976 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    Including: Jackson Hole Preservation Incorporated-Oral History Research Office-Columbia University
  - Correspondence: L, 1964-1977 (Box 4, Folder 38-45, Box 5, Folder 46-51)
    Including: Land Use-Task Force on Land Use and Urban Growth, Land Use-Task Force-Seattle Trip and Correspondence, Land Use-Richard Slavin Report, Land Use-HUD Act of 1970-House and Senate Bill, Land Use-Land Use and Population Distribution Citizens' Committee, Land Use-Phoenix, Arizona, Planning Map and Correspondence, Land Use-California Planning Maps and Correspondence, Land Use-Dade County Florida Planning Maps and Correspondence, Land Use-Atlanta, Georgia, City Planning Maps and Correspondence, Land Use-Hawaii Land Use Law and Implementation, Land Use-Dallas, Texas, Planning Maps and Correspondence, Land Use-Houston, Texas, Planning Maps and Correspondence, The Charles A. Lindbergh Memorial Fund Committee, General
  - Correspondence: M, 1971-1976 (Box 5, Folder 52-53)
    Including: Man and His Urban Environment Project, Man and His Urban Environment
  - Correspondence: N, 1966-1979 (Box 5, Folder 54, Box 6, Folder 55-63, Box 7, Folder 64-66)
    Including: National Associaton of Recycling Industries, National Electrical Manufacturers Association, National Environmental Development Association, National Environmental Test, National Governors' Conference, National Industrial Conference Board, National Industrial Pollution Control Council, National Planning Association, National Rural Electric Cooperative Association, New Towns, Nixon Task Force on Environment, North American Rockwell Speech-Willard Rockwell, General
  - Correspondence: P, 1970-1978 (Box 7, Folder 67-71)
    Including: Parking Industry Pamphlets, Post Office-Mail Permits, President's Seminar-Suggested Procedures, Public Broadcasting Environment Center-Final Report and Abstract, Public Service Commission-New York State
  - Correspondence: R, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    Including: Riverbank State Park
  - Correspondence: S, 1970-1974 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    Including: Solid Waste
  - Correspondence: T, 1967-1977 (Box 7, Folder 74-76)
    Including: Task Force Budget, Industry Task Force on Environment, Task Force Recommendations-The Environment
  - Correspondence: U, 1969-1974 (Box 7, Folder 77-78, Box 8, Folder 79-81)
    Including: United States Atomic Energy Commission, United States Department of the Interior, United States National Commission for UNESCO, Urban Land Institute-Hartford Meeting, General
  - Correspondence: V, 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Correspondence: W, 1968-1976 (Box 8, Folder 83-86)
    Including: Water Resources Council, Western Conference of Public Service Commissions, Winrock International Livestock Research and Training Center, General
- General Files, 1969-1980; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  - Club of Rome - M.I.T., 1972 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Conference on Cities, May 25-28, 1971, Indianapolis, Indiana: Background Material (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Housing Project: Proposals and Synopsis of Housing Letters, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Hudson River Basin: Status of Pure Water Program, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 90-91)
  - "The Quiet Revolution in Land Use Control", Summary Report, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Rockefeller Reels I and II, March 8, 1967, 2017:FA1224:001 (Box 9, Folder 93)
    Separated Materials
    Audio
  - "The Satellite Town", a Work Book prepared for discussion by the Citizens Advisory Comittee (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Miscellaneous Items from Harry Rand's Desk, 1975, 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 95)
- Businessmen and Beautification, 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  - Businessmen and Beautification: Report (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Businessmen and Beautification (Box 9, Folder 97-99, Box 10, Folder 100-102)
- Citizens Advisory Committee on Environmental Quality (CACEQ), 1961-1979; 3.8 Cubic Feet 10 letter document boxes
  - Annual Reports
    - Citizens Advisory Committee on Recreation and Natural Beauty: Annual Reports, 1967, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 103-104)
    - CACEQ: Annual Report, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 105)
    - CACEQ: Annual Report, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 106-108)
      Correspondence - Folders 107 and 108
    - CACEQ: Annual Report, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 109-110, Box 11, Folder 111-112)
      Correspondence - Folder 110; Press Releases - Folder 111; Public Relations - Folder 112
    - CACEQ: Annual Report, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 113-115)
      Correspondence - Folder 114; Press Clippings - Folder 115
    - CACEQ: Annual Report, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 116-117)
      Correspondence - Folder 117
    - CACEQ: Annual Report, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 118-119)
      Correspondence - Folder 119
  - Correspondence
    - CACEQ: Correspondence - A-I, 1961, 1970-1979 (Box 11, Folder 120-128)
    - CACEQ: Correspondence - K-P, 1970-1979 (Box 11, Folder 129, Box 12, Folder 130-134)
    - CACEQ: Correspondence - R-T, 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 135-137)
    - CACEQ: Correspondence - W, 1971-1978 (Box 12, Folder 138)
    - CACEQ: Bureau of Outdoor Recreation, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 139)
    - CACEQ: Government Printing Office, 1973-1976 (Box 12, Folder 140)
    - CACEQ: Hang-on Tags (Box 12, Folder 141)
    - CACEQ: Laurance S. Rockefeller Memo re Power Lines, Hawaii, 1973 November 13 (Box 12, Folder 142)
    - CACEQ: Publications - Order Forms, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 143)
    - CACEQ: Recycling Logo, 1971-1976 (Box 12, Folder 144)
    - CACEQ: Stationery Proofs, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 145)
  - General Files
    - Executive Order Establishing CACEQ, 1966, 1968-1970, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 146)
    - History: 1966-1974, 1970-1976 (Box 12, Folder 147)
    - Energy Sub-Committee, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 148)
  - Meetings
    - CACEQ: Meetings: Minutes of CACEQ Meetings, 1970 February-May (Box 13, Folder 149)
    - CACEQ: Meetings, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 150-151)
      Meetings of August 31, 1970 and November 30, 1970
    - CACEQ: Meetings, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 152-154)
      Meetings of March 19, 1971, June 18, 1971, September 30, 1971
    - CACEQ: Meetings, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 155-157, Box 14, Folder 158-159)
      Meetings of January 12, 1972, April 21, 1972, July 21, 1972, October 27, 1972, December 15-16, 1972
    - CACEQ: Meetings, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 160-162)
      Meetings of March 23, 1973, June 29, 1973, September 9-10, 1973
    - CACEQ: Meetings, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 163-164, Box 15, Folder 165)
      Meetings of January 11, 1974, April 12, 1974, September 29, 1974
    - CACEQ: Meetings, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 166-169)
      Meetings of February 14, 1975, May 30, 1975, July 3, 1975, September 29, 1975
    - CACEQ: Meetings, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 170-172)
      Meetings of January 16, 1976, May 12, 1976, September 24, 1976
  - Publications
    - "Citizen Action Guide to Energy Conservation", 1973-1974 (Box 15, Folder 173-174, Box 16, Folder 175)
      Folder 175 - Clippings
    - "Citizens Make the Difference: Case Studies of Environmental Action", 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 176)
    - "Community Action for Environmental Quality", 1970-1973 (Box 16, Folder 177-179)
    - "Energy in Solid Waste: A Citizen Guide to Saving", 1974-1976 (Box 17, Folder 180-181)
      Folder 181 - Clippings
    - "From Rails to Trails", 1974-1978 (Box 17, Folder 182-183)
      Folder 183 - Clippings
    - "How Will America Grow?: A Citizen Guide to Land Use Planning", 1975-1976 (Box 17, Folder 184)
    - "Individual Action Check List for Energy Conservation in Transportation, Homes and Offices, Industries and Electric Utilities", 1974 (Box 17, Folder 185)
    - "Mission Possible" TV Programs, 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 186)
    - "A New Approach to the Disposal of Liquid Waste", 1968-1971 (Box 18, Folder 187-190, Box 19, Folder 191)
      Folders 188-191 - Liquid Waste Project: Binder
    - "A New Look at Recycling Waste Paper", 1972-1977 (Box 19, Folder 192)
    - Publications Brochures, 1975-1978 (Box 19, Folder 193)
    - Publications Reports, 1973-1976 (Box 19, Folder 194)
  - Reports
    - CACEQ Report: "The Loss of Agricultural Land", Roger Blobaum, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 195)
    - CACEQ Report: The Use of Land, 1971-1973 (Box 19, Folder 196)
- Fred Smith, 1967-1978; 1.9 Cubic Feet 5 letter document boxes
  - Publications and Speeches
    - "America is a Growing Country", 1971-1972 (Box 19, Folder 197-198, Box 20, Folder 199-204)
      Folders 198-200 - Correspondence; Folder 201 - In Other Publications; Folder 202 - Response; Folder 203 - Business Response; Folder 204 - Congressional Response
    - "Atomic Power and Man's Changing Environment", 1967 October (Box 20, Folder 205)
    - "The Corner We Turned in Time", 1972 (Box 20, Folder 206)
    - "In Two Generations This Nation Will Self-Destruct: The Environmental Job", 1970 (Box 21, Folder 207)
    - "Statistics and Patches: What's Wrong in the Cities", 1972 (Box 21, Folder 208)
    - "Liquid Waste Disposal - a Job Man Knows How to Do and Cannot Get Done", 1970 (Box 21, Folder 209)
    - "Man and His Urban Environment", 1971-1978 (Box 21, Folder 210-218, Box 22, Folder 219-223)
      Folders 211-213 - Binder; Folder 214 - An Agenda for the Future; Folder 215 - A Proposal; Folder 216 - A 3-Part Proposal; Folder 217 - Clippings; Folder 218 - Comments; Folder 219 - Envelopes; Folder 220 - Invoice; Folder 221 - Press Release; Folder 222 - Promotion Letters; Folder 223 - What have we learned and some thoughts about where we go from here
    - "A Practical Program for Protecting the Environment", 1969-1970 (Box 22, Folder 224)
    - "To Keep Life on the Move", 1968 (Box 22, Folder 225)
    - "To Win the War on Water Pollution", 1970 (Box 22, Folder 226)
    - "The Way It's Going to Be: An American City - The Year 2000", 1972 (Box 22, Folder 227)
    - "Whatever Happened to the State of the Union?", 1978 (Box 22, Folder 228)
    - "Where Do We Go from Here?" (Box 22, Folder 229)
  - Reports
    - "How Can We Apply Cost-Benefit Analysis to Environmental Improvement?", 1972 May 8 (Box 22, Folder 230)
    - "A New Approach to Federal-State-Local Cooperation in Providing Facilities for Liquid Waste Disposal", 1970 January 20 (Box 22, Folder 231)
    - "Population Congestion in Big Cities and What Can Be Done About It" (Box 22, Folder 232)
    - "Progress Report: Urban Land Use and Population Distribution Project" (Box 22, Folder 233)
  - Speeches
    - "The Natural Beauty Movement and the Power Business", 1967 September 19 (Box 22, Folder 234)
    - "The Anatomy of the Natural Beauty Movement", 1967 October 6 (Box 22, Folder 235)
    - "The Future of the Natural Beauty Movement", 1967 November 1 (Box 22, Folder 236)
    - "Nuclear Plants and the Environment", 1968 March 28 (Box 22, Folder 237)
    - "The Electric Utility Industry and the Environment", 1968 May 24 (Box 22, Folder 238)
    - "To Keep Life on the Move", 1968 June 16 (Box 22, Folder 239)
    - "The Real Significance of the Utility Industry Task Force Report", 1968 September 25 (Box 22, Folder 240)
    - "Report on the Electric Utility Industry Task Force on the Environment", 1968 November 14 (Box 22, Folder 241)
    - Electric Utility Industry Task Force on the Environment, 1969 January 27 (Box 22, Folder 242)
    - "Outer Shelf Lands, Marine Resource Development and Environmental Protection", 1969 February 20 (Box 22, Folder 243)
    - "Public Service Commissions and the Environment", 1969 May 7 (Box 22, Folder 244)
    - "A Practical Program for Protecting the Environment", 1969 May 14 (Box 22, Folder 245)
    - "The Electric Utility Task Force Report – One Year Later", 1969 October 7 (Box 22, Folder 246)
    - "Confessions of an Anti-Hero", 1970 February 17 (Box 22, Folder 247)
    - "Facing the Music", 1970 March 3 (Box 22, Folder 248)
    - "In Two Generations This Nation Will Self-Destruct", 1970 April 15, 1970 May 21 (Box 22, Folder 249-250)
    - "We Have Met the Enemy and He is Us", 1971 March (Box 23, Folder 251)
    - "Communications in the 70's", 1971 April 13 (Box 23, Folder 252)
    - "Some Preliminary Thinking on the Resources Available to Create Cities that Work", 1971 May 26 (Box 23, Folder 253)
    - "The Corner We Turned – In Time", 1971 November 4 (Box 23, Folder 254)
    - "The Way It's Going to Be", 1972 January 18 (Box 23, Folder 255)
    - Statement of M. Frederik Smith – Environmental Panel, 1972 April 19 (Box 23, Folder 256)
    - "Statistics and Patches: Or What's Wrong in the Cities", 1972 October 3 (Box 23, Folder 257)
    - "A New Charter for a New Era – The NPA Moves into the Seventies", 1972 November 10 (Box 23, Folder 258)
    - "Hawaii: A View from the Outside Looking In", 1973 June 21 (Box 23, Folder 259)
    - "Where Do We Go From Here? A Proposal for NPA's Second Generation", 1973 November 27 (Box 23, Folder 260)
    - "The Influence of Transportation on the Quality of Growth in Hawaii", 1973 December 6 (Box 23, Folder 261)
    - "After the Ball is Over or The Search for a Practical Program to Protect the Environment and Preserve Society without Wrecking a Lot of Other Things or You Can't Fix Merely One Thing", 1974 March 25 (Box 23, Folder 262)
    - "Society and the Private Sector", 1974 November 19 (Box 23, Folder 263)
    - "In Search of an Intelligent Agenda for a Bicentennial", 1975 May 13 (Box 23, Folder 264)
    - "Electricity, the Quality of Life, the Courts, and the Future", 1977 June 15 (Box 23, Folder 265)
    - "The Ball is in Our Court: Let's Not Fumble It", 1977 September 19 (Box 23, Folder 266)
- Grand Teton National Park, 1950-1978; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  - Grand Teton National Park, 1950, 1967, 1971-1978 (Box 23, Folder 267-269)
  - Grand Teton National Park: Jackson Hole Airport, 1973, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 270, Box 24, Folder 271)
- Utilities, 1965-1973; 2.28 Cubic Feet 6 letter document boxes
  - "The Role of the Utility Industry in the Quality of Our Environment", 1965-1966 (Box 24, Folder 272)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller Speech of November 30, 1966, and Research Material
  - "The Electric Utility Industry and the Environment", 2nd Printing (Box 24, Folder 273)
  - Electric Utility Industry Undergrounding Excerpts (Box 24, Folder 274)
  - Electric Utility Task Force on Environment: Binder (Box 24, Folder 275)
  - Clippings, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 276)
  - Electric Utility Industry Task Force on Environment, Minutes, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 277-278)
    Folder 277 - June 15 and 16, 1967; Folder 278 - October 19, 1967 Meeting
  - Electric Utility Industry Task Force on Environment: Proceedings, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 279-281)
    Folder 279 - March 12, 1968; Folders 280-281 - June 20, 1968
  - Electric Utility Industry Task Force on Environment: Task Force Questionnaire, Final Copy, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 282)
  - Report of the Electric Utility Industry Task Force on Environment: Draft Report, First Part, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 283)
  - Working Committee on Utilities: Report to the Vice President and to the President's Council on Recreation and Natural Beauty, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 284-285)
  - Federal Power Commission: National Power Survey Advisory Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 286)
  - Federal Power Survey: Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 26, Folder 287)
  - "A Commitment to Change – Utilities, Regulators and Conservationists", Remarks of Lelan F. Sillin, Jr., 1970 April 30 (Box 26, Folder 288)
  - Federal Power Commission National Power Survey Task Force on Environment Meeting, 1971 April 6 (Box 26, Folder 289)
  - Federal Power Survey: Correspondence and Memos by Fred Smith, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 290)
  - Federal Power Commission: Task Force Report – Final Draft, 1971 April 20 (Box 27, Folder 291)
  - Federal Power Commission: National Power Survey: Chapter XXI – "Regulation of the Electric Power Industry" (Box 27, Folder 292)
  - Public Service Commission Hearings on the Advisability of Undergrounding Utility Distribution Systems: Background Materials, 1968-1971 (Box 27, Folder 293-294)
  - Public Service Commission Hearing, March 6, 1971: Testimony of H. Rand for F. Smith (Box 27, Folder 295, Box 28, Folder 296)
  - Public Utility Commissions, 1972-1973 (Box 28, Folder 297-299)
    Folder 298 - New York; Folder 299 - Maryland
  - Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 300)
  - Distribution Lines, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 301)
  - Transmission Lines (Box 29, Folder 302)
  - Case Studies – Underground Utilities, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 303)
  - Power Plant Siting, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 304)
  - Legislation, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 305)
  - Research and Development, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 306)
  - Miscellaneous, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 307)
  - "Energy in the City Environment: 1972-1985" Conference, New York City, May 18, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 308)
  - The Salt River Project's Underground Residential Distribution and Power Styling of Substations and Overhead Power Lines (Box 29, Folder 309)
  - Salt River Project: Film, 2017:FA1224:002 (Box 29, Folder 310)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access copy unavailable. Please contact an RAC archivist for further instruction.
- Rockefeller Family: Public Relations, 1915-1978; 1.14 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes
  - "The Rockefeller Image: An Objective Appraisal" by Chase Manhattan Bank, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 311)
  - Public Relations Conference, October 17, 1969: Correspondence (Box 29, Folder 312)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Public Opinion Survey, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 313)
  - Lou Harris: Correspondence, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 314)
  - Lloyd A. Free Survey: Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 29, Folder 315)
  - Proceedings, Public Relations Conference, October 17, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 316)
  - Public Opinion Survey – Memos to the Family, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 317)
  - Public Opinion Survey – Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 318)
  - Public Relations Conference, February 27, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 319)
  - Proceedings, Public Relations Conference, February 27, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 320)
  - Public Relations Conference, April 8-10, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 321)
  - Proceedings, Public Relations Conference, April 9, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 322)
  - "Public Attitudes Toward the Rockefellers" by Lloyd A. Free, 1970 September 26 (Box 30, Folder 323)
  - Public Relations Conference, December 7, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 324)
  - Proceedings, Meeting of the Rockefeller Family and Associates, December 7, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 325)
  - Distribution of Rockefeller Books to the Public Relations Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 30, Folder 326)
  - Harry Rand Public Relations Conference Memos, 1970-1971 (Box 30, Folder 327)
  - Public Relations Conference, December 6, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 328)
  - Proceedings, Public Relations Conference, December 6, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 329)
  - Pocantico Outing, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 330)